A Finding Aid to the Jacques Lipchitz papers and Bruce Bassett papers concerning Jacques Lipchitz, 1910-2001, bulk 1941-2001, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Jacques Lipchitz papers, circa 1910-1999; bulk 1941-1999; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973; Bassett, Bruce W.; 9.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-10, OV 11-12
  - Correspondence, 1926-1975; 1.2; Archival Resource Key; 4.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-5, OV 11
    - New York City Community College - Niemeyer, Oscar, 1942-1970, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31)
      New York City Community College
      New York City, Department of Public Works
      New York Guild for the Jewish Blind
      New York Herald Tribune
      New York Post
      New York Psychoanalytic Institute
      New York Public Library
      New York Studio School of Drawing, Painting and Sculpture
      New York Times
      New York University
      Nicolas, J.
      Niemeyer, Oscar
    - Noailles, Charles de, Viscount (photocopies), 1927-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Northside Center for Child Development, Inc. - Nubgaard, Betty, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Northside Center for Child Development, Inc.
      Noyes, Eliot, Jr.
      Nubgaard, Betty
    - Oberlin College, Dudley Peter Allen Memorial Art Museum - Otto Gerson Gallery, Inc., 1951-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Oberlin College, Dudley Peter Allen Memorial Art Museum
      Observer (London)
      O'Connor, Patricia
      O'Connor and Kilham, Jr., Architects
      L'Oeil Revue d'Art
      Office National de Tourisme Hellenique
      Oldham, Gail P.
      Old Westbury Gardens, Inc.
      Oliver, Katharine S.
      Omaha National Bank
      Orain, J.
      Oram, Harold L.
      Orion Press
      Orswell, Lois
      Oscar Meyer Antique Works of Art, Inc.
      Otis Art Institute of Los Angeles County
      Otten, Albert
    - Owen, Jane Blaffer, circa 1950-1969; Archival Resource Key; 3 Folders (Box 3, Folder 35-37)
    - Ozenfant, Amèdèe - Passedoit, Georgette, 1945-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 38)
      Ozenfant, Amèdèe
      Pach, Walter
      Painters and Sculptors Society of New Jersey, Inc.
      Pannaggi, Ivo
      Pasaye, Michele
      Passedoit, Georgette
    - Patai, Irene, 1961-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Pattison, Abbott - Peiser, Donald, 1953-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 40)
      Pattison, Abbott
      Paul F. Damaz, Architect
      Paul Moro, Inc., Restorer of Paintings
      Paul Rosenberg and Co.
      Peiser, Donald
    - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1950-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Peridot Gallery - Philadelphia Museum College of Art, 1953-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 42)
      Peridot Gallery
      Perls Galleries (New York)
      Perrine, A. J.
      Persian Antique Gallery
      Peter Marks Works of Art, Inc.
      P. F. Collier and Son Corporation
      Philadelphia, City of
      Philadelphia Friends of Lubavitch
      Philadelphia Museum College of Art
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1950-1968; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 43-44)
    - Philadelphia Museum School of Art - Pitman Publishing Corporation, 1943-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 45)
      Oversized material housed in OV 11, F3
      Philadelphia Museum School of Art
      Philip Johnson Associates
      Pickens, Alton
      Pietroseal, Remo, Jr.
      Piñata Party, Inc.
      Pine Plains Central School District (NY)
      Piper, Raymond F.
      Pitman Publishing Corporation
    - Plass, Mrs. Webster - Portable Gallery Press, 1945-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 46)
      Plass, Mrs. Webster
      Play Schools Association Inc.
      Pleiss, Margo
      Poe, Barbara Reis
      Pollack, Jack Harrison
      Pomerance, Harriet and Leon
      Pomerance and Breines Architects
      Pomfret School
      Portable Gallery Press
    - Portland Art Museum, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Portland Museum Art School - Ragon, Sara, 1944-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Portland Museum Art School
      Powers, Judith
      Praeger, B. M.
      Pratt Institute
      Prentice-Hall, Inc.
      Primus Gallery
      Princeton University, Art Museum
      Prisme des Arts
      Prochnik, Wit-Olaf
      Pro Civitate Christiana
      Provincetown Art Association Incorporated
      Public Education Association
      Purris, J. J.
      Quamme, Norman
      Racine Art Foundry
      Racolin, Alexander E.
      Rácz, Andre
      Radcliffe Institute for Independent Study
      Radiodiffusion-Télévision Française
      Radziminski, Wayne Lee
      Raemith, Waldemar
      Rafi, Samir
      Ragon, Sara
    - Rannit, Aleksis - Redstone, Louis G. and Ruth, 1952-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Oversized material housed in OV 11, F4
      Rannit, Aleksis
      Rapoport, Morris
      Rapoport, Natan
      Rassegna Internazionale di Scultura Contemporanea all'Aperto, 2a
      Ray, Deborah Cohen
      Raynal, Germaine and M.
      Read, Prudence
      Rechter Zary Architects, Peri Engineer
      Reder, Bernard
      Redstone, Louis G. and Ruth
    - Refess-Remisoff, Michel and Hélène - Reform Jewish Appeal, 1954-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Refess-Remisoff, Michel and Hélène
      Reform Jewish Appeal
    - Reis, Bernard and Becky; Reis, Barbara, 1952-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Rewald, John - Rienckens, Valentin, 1943-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Rewald, John
      Rey, Sydor
      Rhode Island School of Design, The Museum
      Rice, Norman N.
      Richter, Horace
      Rienckens, Valentin
    - Rijksmuseum Kröller Muller Otterlo, 1953-1968, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Rimberg, Herman - Rosch, Mrs. Samuel J., 1943-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Rimberg, Herman
      Rina Gallery
      Ringelheim, Paul H.
      Ritter, Gladys
      Robbins, Dorothy
      Robinson, George F.
      Rockefeller, Mrs. John D., III
      Rockefeller, Mary C.
      Rockefeller, Nelson A.
      Rodgers, William
      Rodman, Selden
      Romain Rolland Memorial Meeting
      Rome, Harold
      Ronnebeck, Arnold
      Rood, Dorothy B. A.
      Rosch, Mrs. Samuel J.
    - Rose, Billy - Rozran, Bernard W., 1950-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Rose, Billy
      Rosen, Jack
      Rosen, Samuel
      Rosenbaum, Helen
      Rosenberg, Natalie
      Rosenberg, James N.
      Rosenfeld, Louis
      Rosenthal, Julius
      Rosgate, Theodore
      Ross, Gloria and Arthur
      Roston, Arnold
      Roth, Irene
      Roth, Sanford H.
      Rotsch, Kurt
      Rousset, Robert
      Rowlings, Arnie
      Royal-Athena Galleries
      Rozran, Bernard W.
    - Rubin, Samuel - R.V. Replogle and M. G. Barr, Designers and Directors of Apex, 1955-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Rubin, Samuel
      Rubinow, Raymond S.
      Rubinson, Nathan
      Rubinstein, Marla
      Rudier, G.
      Rumsey, Claire
      Ruslander, Selwyn D.
      Russell, Dick and Steph
      Russell, George
      R.V. Replogle and M. G. Barr, Designers and Directors of Apex
    - Sadwith, Lucille - Sarah Lawrence College, 1951-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Sadwith, Lucille
      Sahl, Hans
      Saint Cloud State College
      St. Joseph Museum
      St. Paul Gallery and School of Art
      Sts. John and Paul School (Larchmont, NH)
      Salcius, Mr. A.
      Salmony, Alfred
      Sandberg, Willem
      Sanders, P.
      San Francisco Civic Center Plaza International Competition
      San Francisco Museum of Art
      Sarah Lawrence College
    - Scarsdale Studio Workshop - Schneersohn, I., 1957-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Scarsdale Studio Workshop (NY)
      Scarsdale Synagogue (NY)
      Scarsdale Woman's Club (NY)
      Schaap, Adolf
      Schack, William
      Schalz, Belle K.
      Schapiro, Meyer and Lillian
      Schendel, Jim
      Scher, Marie
      Schmid, Elsa
      Schneersohn, I.
    - Schneerson, Menachem M., 1959-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Schneid, Otto - Sculptors Guild, Incorporated, 1942-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Schneid, Otto
      Schneider, Alexander
      Schocken, Gidon
      Schor, Ilya
      Schuling, I. W.
      Schwartz, Alan E.
      Schwarz, Karl
      Schweich, Albert
      Schweicher, Curt
      Schweighofer, F.
      Schweinhage, Karin M. E.
      Sculptors Guild, Incorporated
    - Seattle World's Fair - Sextant, Inc., 1944-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
      Seattle World's Fair
      Seckler, Dorothy
      Segel, Yonny
      Segy Gallery
      Seiden, Rudolph
      Setterblad, Oscar
      Sexology
      Sextant, Inc.
    - Shapiro, Jessie - Silvermine Guild of Artists, Inc., 1952-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Shapiro, Jessie
      Shaw, Frederick W.
      Shaye, Max M.
      Sherer, Morris
      Sherman, Devora
      Sherod
      Shikes, Peter B.
      Shopen, Ken
      Shore, Donald
      Shorewood Publishers Inc.
      Show
      Sichel, Pierre
      Sicilia, Salvatore
      Sikkens Lakfabrieken
      Silber, Zavel
      Silvermine Guild of Artists, Inc.
    - Simms, Carroll H. - Smithsonian Institution, National Collection of Fine Arts, 1953-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Simms, Carroll H.
      Sinai Temple (Los Angeles)
      Singer, Herbert M.
      Singer, Mimi
      Skidmore, Owings and Merrill, Architects/Engineers
      Sleepy Hollow Restorations
      Sloan, Mrs. N. P.
      Smith College Museum of Art
      Smith, Hinchman and Grylls Associates, Inc.
      Smith, Jean Kennedy
      Smithsonian Institution, National Collection of Fine Arts
    - Smoter, Jerzy - Sonnenfeld, Otto, 1949-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
      Smoter, Jerzy
      Soby, James T.
      Sobsy, Cynthia
      Société des Amis d'Yvan Goll
      Société Radio-Canada
      Society of Washington Artists
      Soderberg, Ronald
      Sofianopulo, Cesare
      Solomon, Betty M.
      Solomon, Gerald
      Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum
      Sonnenberg, Benjamin
      Sonnenfeld, Otto
    - Soula, Camille, 1951-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Southworth, June - Soyer, Raphael, 1962-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
      Southworth, June
      Soyer, Raphael
    - Spaeth, Eloise, 1962-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Spalek, Paul - Stankiewicz, Richard, 1946-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Spalek, Paul
      Spampinato, Mario
      Spanish Refugee Aid, Inc.
      Spanish Refugee Appeal
      Spire Production Company
      Spring, Betty
      Spring, John C.
      Springfield Art League (MA)
      Squier, Jack
      Stadt Duisberg Kunstmuseum
      Stadt Köln
      Stadtische Kunstsammlungen, Nuremberg
      Städtisches Museum Wuppertal
      Staempfli, George W.
      Stankiewicz, Richard
    - Starrels, Joel and Celeste, 1958-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Starwood Corporation - Stavisky, Lotte, 1949-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Starwood Corporation
      State of Israel Bonds
      State of Israel Commemoration Dinner
      State University of Iowa
      Stavisky, Lotte
    - Stedelijk Museum (Amsterdam), 1955-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Stedelijk Museum "Het Prinsehof" (Delft) - Stephens, Jacqueline, 1928-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
      Stedelijk Museum "Het Prinsehof" (Delft)
      Stedelijk van Abbe-museum (Eindhoven)
      Steegmuller, Francis
      Steendrukkerij de Jong and Co.
      Stein, Gertrude (photocopies)
      Stein, Jules
      Steinbeck, Dietmar
      Steinman, Mr. and Mrs.
      Stephens College
      Stephens, Jacqueline
    - Sterling, Friede and Bob - Tafel, Edgar, 1944-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
      Sterling, Friede and Bob
      Stern, Herbert
      Stern, Louis E.
      Stern, Simone
      Streeter, Tal
      Strutz, Henry
      Stuart Art Gallery
      Sunday Courier and Press (Evansville, IN)
      Sweeney, James Johnson
      Swet, Gershon
      Tacha, Athena C.
      Tafel, Edgar
    - Taft, Robert, Jr., 1957-1960, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Talner, Gabrielov, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Tamarind Lithography Workshops, Inc., 1962-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Tasutzky, Boris - Teochita, Inc., Pre-Columbian Art, 1952-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Tasutzky, Boris
      Tate Gallery
      Taylor, Larry P.
      Taylor, Sandra
      Tell, Philip
      Teller, Walter Magnes
      Temerman, Nadia
      The Temple (Cleveland)
      Temple Beth El (Flint, MI)
      Temple B'nai Sholom
      Temple Emanu-el of Long Beach (NY)
      Temple Israel (Croton-on-Hudson, NY)
      Temple Israel of Northern Westchester (NY)
      Temple Sinai of Bergen County (NJ)
      Tenenbaum, Sheu
      Teochita, Inc., Pre-Columbian Art
    - Thaler, Pat - Tishman, Ruth W., 1945-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
      Thaler, Pat
      Thalheimer, Lilyan J.
      Thannhauser, Justin K.
      Thebault, Janine
      Thebault, P. F.
      Theodor Herzl Institute
      This Week Magazine
      Thomas, Steffen
      Thompson, G. David
      Thompson, Gladys
      Ticho, Anna
      Tillinghast, Caroline and Frank
      Time
      Times Herald Record (Middletown, NY)
      Tishman, Paul
      Tishman, Ruth W.
    - Tobak, David - Tovish, Harold, 1952-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33)
      Tobak, David
      Tobias, Frances
      Toledo Museum of Art
      Tombeau du Martyr Juif Inconnu
      Tommasi, Paolo
      Tompkins, Alfred E.
      Tournai [Belgium], Municipality of
      Tovish, Harold
    - Trepuk, Albert O. - Union of Hebrew American Congregations, Commission on Synagogue Administration, 1947-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 34)
      Trepuk, Albert O.
      Trier, Eduard
      Trotsky, Hélène
      Trumbull Jewish Community Group (CT)
      Tuchman, Mr.
      Tucker, Jean S.
      Tung Hsun-Chung
      Turnbull, Grace H.
      Turn Toward Peace, New England Regional Office
      l'Union des Artistes, Centenaire Toulouse-Lautrec
      Union des Sociétés Juives de France
      Union of Hebrew American Congregations, Commission on Synagogue Administration
    - United Church Board for Homeless Ministries - University of California, 1942-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 35)
      United Church Board for Homeless Ministries
      United Church of Christ (Philadelphia)
      United Hebrew Congregation (St. Louis)
      United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York
      United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO)
      United Presbyterian Church
      United States Department of State
      United States Information Agency
      United States Treasury Department
      United States War Information Office
      United States War Production Board
      Universal Limited Art Editions
      University of California
    - University of California, Los Angeles, Art Galleries, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - University of California, Los Angeles, Art Galleries, 1963-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - University of Chicago - University of Kansas, Museum of Art, 1946-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 38)
      University of Chicago
      University of Denver
      University of Hartford
      University of Illinois, Krannert Art Museum
      University of Kansas
      University of Kansas, Museum of Art
    - University of Minnesota, Duluth, 1961-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 39)
      Oversized material housed in OV 11, F5
    - University of Minnesota, Duluth, 1964-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - University of Oregon - University of Pennsylvania, 1950-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 41)
      University of Oregon
      University of Pennsylvania
    - University of Pennsylvania, University Museum, 1951-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - University of Pennsylvania, University Museum, 1960-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - University of St. Thomas (Houston) - Vacheron, Edilbert Z., 1953-1969, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 44)
      University of St. Thomas (Houston)
      University of Southern California
      University of Texas
      University of Toronto
      University of Vermont
      University of Washington
      University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee
      Uris Building Corporation
      Uzielli, Mrs. Giorgio
      Vacheron, Edilbert Z.
    - Valentin, Curt, Estate of, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Van Bork, Bert, 1960-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Vancouver Art Gallery - Vermont Marble Company, 1951-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 47)
      Vancouver Art Gallery
      van der Blij, K. J.
      van der Marck, J.H.M.
      van der Wal, G.
      van Leyden, Karin
      Van Waveren, Godfried
      Varèse, Edgard
      Varkell, Paul
      Vaughn, Rosa E.
      Verdel, A.
      Verhagen, Joep
      Verlag Kurt Desch München
      Vermont Marble Company
    - Victor Kamkin, Inc. Bookstore - Vilven, Marsha L., 1945-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 48)
      Victor Kamkin, Inc. Bookstore
      Victoria and Albert Museum
      View
      Villanueva, Carlos Raúl
      Vilven, Marsha L.
    - Vincent G. Kling and Associates, 1966-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - Waits, Don, 1945-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 50)
      Virginia Museum of Fine Arts
      Vizer, Mr.
      Vogel, Virginia Booth
      Vogue
      Vose Galleries of Boston, Inc.
      Waits, Don
    - Walker Art Center, 1954-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Walker Foundation - Weill, Erna, 1948-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Walker Foundation
      Walker, Maynard
      Wall Street Synagogue
      Walters Art Gallery
      Warren, Katherine
      Warshaw, Howard
      Warszawski, Marie
      Washington Hebrew Congregation
      Washton, Rose-Carol
      Watson, Thomas J., Jr.
      Waxman, Bertha B.
      W. B. Yeats Memorial Committee
      WCAU-TV 10
      W. C. Cox and Company
      Webb, Aline
      Weidenfeld and Nicolson Limited
      Weil, Florence
      Weill, Erna
    - Weiner, Aline - Welton Becket and Associates, Architects, Engineers, 1945-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Weiner, Aline
      Weiner, Egon
      Weiner, Lillian
      Weiner, Martin
      Weiner, Norman and Eugenia
      Weiner, Ted
      Weintraub Gallery
      Weisman, David
      Weiss, Florence
      Weizmann Institute of Science
      Welton Becket and Associates, Architects, Engineers
    - Weng, Siegfried R. - White, Robert W., 1944-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Weng, Siegfried R.
      Wenger, J.
      Werner, Alfred
      Westchester Art Society (NY)
      Westchester Arts and Crafts Guild (NY)
      Westchester Co., Commissioner of Jurors (NY)
      Westchester Day School (NY)
      Westchester Reform Temple (Hartsdale, NY)
      Westheim, Raul
      WGBH-FM and WGBH-TV (Cambridge, MA)
      White House
      White, Robert W.
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1945-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Wholden, Rosalind G. - William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, Atkins Museum of Fine Arts, 1952-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Wholden, Rosalind G.
      Who's Who
      Who's Who in America
      Wichita State University
      Wiggins, Jim
      Wilber, Thomas Brown
      Willard, Charlotte
      Willard Gallery
      William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, Atkins Museum of Fine Arts
    - Williams, Jack and Zeta - Wookey, Richard H., 1943-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Williams, Jack and Zeta
      Willis, Mrs. John T.
      Wills, Frances
      Wilson, Helen
      Wines, James
      Winnepeg Art Gallery Association/Winnepeg Art Gallery
      Wittenborn, George
      Wittlich, Peter
      Women for Peace
      Wookey, Richard H.
    - Worcester Art Museum, 1943-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - World Federation of the Bergen-Belson Associations, Inc. - WUHY-FM (Philadelphia), 1956-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8)
      World Federation of the Bergen-Belson Associations, Inc.
      World House
      WRCV (Philadelphia)
      W. R. Keating and Company
      W. S. Budworth and Son, Inc.
      WUHY-FM (Philadelphia)
    - Wurtzburger, Alan and Janet - Yale Literary Magazine, 1952-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Wurtzburger, Alan and Janet
      Yale and Towne Manufacturing Company
      Yale Literary Magazine
    - Yale University - Yale University Art Gallery, undated; 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Yale University
      Yale University Art Gallery
    - Yamasaki, Minoru - Ysla, Pedro and Gloria, 1944-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Yamasaki, Minoru
      Yamin, Martina
      Yarre, L.
      Yeshiva University, Albert Einstein College of Medicine
      YKUF Art Section
      Yonkers Art Association
      Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association
      Young, Philip A.
      Youth Aliyah and Fellowship in Israel for Arab-Jewish Youth
      Ysla, Pedro and Gloria
    - Zabriskie, Fanny and Vic - Zymet, Carl L., 1952-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Zabriskie, Fanny and Vic
      Zach, Jan
      Zacks, Samuel J.
      Zajac, A.
      Zborowski-Bonat, Josephine
      Zeisler, Richard S.
      Zuck, Tom
      Zucker, Henry L.
      Zymet, Carl L.
    - Unidentified (Alfredo - Frankie), 1958-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Alfredo
      Alice K.
      André
      Claire
      Emilia
      Falya
      Falya and Nina
      Frankie
    - Unidentified (Gertrude and Bill - Marc), 1952-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Gertrude and Bill
      Gigi
      Giorgio
      Gottfried and Tutti
      Jane
      Jane and Tom
      Janine
      Jean
      Jo
      Joe
      Joel
      John
      Johnnie
      Libby and Louis
      Marc
    - Unidentified (Marie-Eve - Natasha), 1954-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Marie-Eve
      Marjo
      Martin
      Natasha
    - Unidentified (Nina - The Zs), 1959-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Nina
      Nino and Marilyn
      Oksana
      Pablo
      Paul
      Pierre
      Ray and M.L.S.
      Sarah
      Sidney
      The Zs
    - Unidentified (Ami - To Whom it May Concern), 1942-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Ami
      Chers
      Cherie
      Directeur et Ami
      Monsieur le Directeur
      Frau
      Friends
      Madame
      Monsieur
      Monsieur et Ami
      Monsieur le President
      Rabbi
      Rebbe
      Sisters and All Our Own
      Sir
      To Whom it May Concern
    - Drafts of Lipchitz's Letters (multiple letters per page), circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Allen, Miss
      Anderson, Mr.
      Aronson, Prof.
      Birchinsky, Mr.
      Byron, Charles A. (Byron Gallery, Inc.)
      Darland, Dr. R. W. (University of Minnesota, Duluth)
      Edelsberg, Mr.
      Fox, Mr.
      Hills, Miss
      Hursh, Mrs.
      [Ingersoll], Sturgis
      Jacobson, Mrs.
      Karsh, Mrs.
      Kling, Vincent
      [Kollek], Teddy
      Mackler, Paul and Hope (Makler Gallery)
      Miró, Joan
      Moore, Henry
      Murphy, Chancellor
      Picasso, Pablo
      Redom, Miss